PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Technician and **Military Veteran** with 5+ years of professional project planning, resource allocation, dispatching, and team leadership experience. **Supervised programs valued in excess of \$20K** and ensured accurate data support and report procedures. Ensured **100% accuracy** of records, reports, and data entry initiatives. Dedication to excellence recognized through being awarded the Air Force Commendation Medal. Career supported by experience in the private sector, United States Air Force, and a **Bachelor of Science in Geography** from the University of Wisconsin – La Crosse.

- Program Operations
- Leadership Initiative
- Data Analysis
- Process Improvement
- Training & Development
- Policy Implementation
- ArcGis
- Communication
- Microsoft Office Suite

EDUCATION

Master of Science – Geographic Information Science – University of Wisconsin – Madison – Currently Enrolled Bachelor of Science – Archeological & Geographic Information Science – University of Wisconsin – La Crosse

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

COUNCIL FOR EDUCATIONAL TRAVEL, USA - La Crosse, WI. Oct 2016- Current/Part time 5 hours Community Placement Coordinator

- · Advertise and network to identify qualified host families and local exchange students
- Secure high school acceptance for students
- Place, monitor, and assist international high school exchange students throughout exchange
- Interview, monitor and assist families throughout the exchange

HERBERGERS - La Crosse, WI. Holiday Stocker/Unloader

Nov 2016 - Dec 2016 / Part time 20 hours

- Unloaded shipments, processed new merchandise, and outgoing orders
- Supported selling floor associates, provided customer service, and stocked home department merchandise

NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC — Washington, D.C. Social Media & Outreach Geography Intern

May 2014- Aug 2014/Full time 40 Hours

- Facilitated the creation, distribution, and monitoring of 100+ pieces of daily content for social media platforms within the education program
- Conducted product tests to identify discrepancies during the creation of the Geo-education community on the Gooru platform; provided reports and recommendations to promote 100% program continuation
- Utilized 3+ social media outlets to promote National Geographic Education resources to a community of over 100,000 subscribers

UNITED STATES GEOLOGICAL SURVEY (USGS) – La Crosse, WI Dec 2012– Dec 2013/Part time 9 Hours

Geographic Information System Intern

- Created and interpreted over 10 river maps using the ArcGis program to cover federal lands and improve resource management
- Scanned, georeferenced, and **digitized 1,000 sq. miles** of area along the Mississippi river in order to classify land use, cover, and pool changes

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN – La Crosse, WI Photography Lab Assistant

Sept 2010- May 2011/Part time 10 Hours

- Devised and implemented the official lab manual for photo lab workers to ensure 100% consistency during daily initiatives and troubleshooting measures
- Supervised the scheduling, student use, equipment management, and photography darkroom valued in excess of \$20K, to promote safe and responsible handling of hazardous materials

UNITED STATES AIR FORCE – Various Locations Senior Maintenance Operational Controller

July 1998-July 2007/Full time 40+ Hours

- Monitored, scheduled, and directed the maintenance programs for 2 military airframes and multiple civilian aircraft to ensure 100% compliance with Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) regulations
- Conducted daily briefings and reports for \$20M worth of airframes, support material, tools, and communication equipment
- Supervised a team of 10+ employees in program checklists, safety operations, and diagnostic programs
- Performed counseling on a 30 day cycle to ensure employees maintained a comprehensive understanding of career objectives and professional improvement

Logistics Supervisor

- Coordinated the maintenance, repair, and troubleshooting of internal and external components on 33 cargo aircraft; identified safety and operational deficiencies and developed time based solutions
- Inspected and ordered 500+ individual parts for installation and upgrades to department systems; verified proper installation and generated maintenance reports
- Trained, mentored, and supervised a team of 5+ individuals in resource management, safety programs, regulation compliance, and process improvement

CERTIFICATIONS

- Total Research Training Certification National Geographic
- Lean Phase II United States Air Force
- Leadership Development Course United States Air Force

NOTABLE AWARDS

- Air Force Commendation Medal
- · Air Force Outstanding Unit Award
- Dean's List

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Adobe Flash, Illustrator, ArcMap, Dreamweaver, Map Box, PowerPoint, Photoshop
- Software: Microsoft Office, SharePoint
- Operating Systems: Mac / Microsoft Windows
- Programming: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, KML